

TECHNICAL LEADERSHIP · TECHNOLOGY CONSULTING

A Columbus, OH | ■ igor@rationalform.com | % igor.fer.st | 🗘 igorferst | 🛅 igorferst

Summary _

Experienced technologist with a track record of high-impact roles at growth-stage software companies and as an independent consultant.

Deep and diverse skill set spanning full-stack development, product management, engineering management, machine learning, and technical training.

Domain expertise in healthcare, capital markets, and insurance.

Work Experience

Rational Form, Ltd. Columbus, OH

OWNER Apr. 2016 - present

- Owner of technology consulting and custom software development business. I use strategic product thinking and deep technical expertise to help my clients meet business goals by leveraging modern software tools.
- Projects include web front-end for a consumer product safety and performance testing tool, back-end API design, and staff augmentation for a high-growth, VC-backed tech company.
- Manage all aspects of client engagements from weekly status reports to billing, operations, and subcontracting.

Root Insurance Columbus, OH

Senior Software Engineer Sept. 2018 - present

- Multiple high-impact projects at a high-growth insuretech startup, including expanding insurance business to new markets, enhancing end-user mobile app, and using machine learning to improve the accuracy of insurance rates.
- Python SME for engineering and data science teams.
- Assist data science team with defining and planning engineering work to support scaling data science across the company.

Aver Inc. Columbus, OH

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sept. 2014 - Feb. 2018

- Led the cross-functional team that built Aver's Virtual Payer, a care management and revenue cycle management product for surgical centers. My team took this product from idea to production application with paying customers.
- Owned product design and technical architecture, maintained product roadmap, implemented APIs and features.
- Grew developer team from 4 to 13: overhauled interview process to emphasize rigor and consistency, defined onboarding process and personally onboarded most new developers. Coached two direct reports through promotion to senior engineer.
- Introduced and trained engineering team on new technologies (Docker, Angular), development processes (TDD, code reviews, release process) and agile methodology (user stories, estimation).

InSample Inc.

San Francisco, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2014 - Sept. 2014

- First employee at healthcare analytics startup building a web-based tool for data exploration and statistical de-biasing of clinical experiments; designed and built the product protoype together with the CTO.
- Prepared fundraising materials and interviewed prospective customers.

Google Inc.

Mountain View, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2014

- Implemented a novel conversion tracking visualization (patent pending) for the AdWords suite of analytics tools.
- Acted as Angular SME during team's transition from legacy front-end framework to Angular.
- · Researched and recommended enhancements to Google Analytics machine-learning algorithm for attribution modeling.

Palantir Technologies Inc.

Palo Alto, CA

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT ANALYST / SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2011 - Jan. 2013

- Embedded with a prominent global macro hedge fund, the largest customer for Palantir's capital markets analytics platform.
- Conducted user interviews and gathered product requirements to help drive product development based on market needs.
- Product owner for platform's visualization and reporting features.
- Transitioned to engineering team to implement visualization and reporting feature roadmap.

NOVEMBER 25, 2018 IGOR FERST · RÉSUMÉ

Technology

Languages/Frameworks Python, Ruby/Rails, Javascript/Angular/React/Node.JS, Java

Infrastructure AWS, Docker, Ansible, SQL

Machine Learning Random forests, vector-based NLP, Markov chains

Patents_

2015 Radial display generation and interactive system, Google Inc. (pending)

2018 Systems and methods for providing episode-based medical care, Aver Inc. (in preparation)

Education

Cornell University Ithaca, NY

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- PhD candidate in Applied Mathematics supported by a National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship.
- Published original research on probabilistic optimization algorithms: https://tinyurl.com/ycheu4us

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, Ontario

M.MATH. IN COMBINATORICS & OPTIMIZATION

University of Chicago

Chicago, IL

B.S. IN MATHEMATICS WITH HONORS

Volunteering

Tech Elevator Columbus, OH

• Panelist and student mentor for local software developer bootcamp.

United Schools Network

Columbus, OH

- Multiple years volunteering for a local charter school network.
- · Designed and taught a three month after-school programming course for middle-school students.
- Developed spreadsheet-based operational tools for school administrators.

Columbus Arts Festival Columbus, OH

- Member of organizing committee for 2016 and 2017 festivals.
- Created an interactive on-line festival map: https://github.com/igorferst/columbus-arts-festival-map
- Interviewed vendors for mobile app development.